Ougi Dark
Part Two
Ougi-chan... is an apparition?
扇ちゃんが 怪異?
On what basis, Gaen-san, are you
calling Ougi-chan a monster?
何を根拠に 臥煙さんは扇ちゃんを
化物だなんて呼ぶんです?
Then on what basis do you call
Ougi Oshino "Ougi-chan"?
ならばきみは 何を根拠に忍野扇を
扇ちゃんなんて呼ぶのかな?
Aren't you merely calling her "Ougi-chan"
because she called herself Ougi Oshino,
彼女が忍野扇と名乗ったから それを鵜呑みにして
彼女を "扇ちゃん" と呼んでいるだけなんじゃあないのかい?
and you just believed her?
It's unlike you to be so
dense about this, Araragi-san.
らしくもなく勘が鈍いですね
阿良々木さん
I'm guessing that this Ougi Oshino-san
was introduced to you by Kanbaru-san,
察するに その忍野扇さんというかたは
バスケットボール部の元スター
the previous star of the basketball team,
as one of her fans?
神原さんのファンとして
彼女から紹介されたのですよね?
Yeah, that's how things went.
ああ... そういう流れだった
A fan. In other words, a fan (ougi).
ファン つまり扇でしょう
Eh? But what about her last name?
え... でも じゃあ苗字のほうはどうなる?
The last name "Oshino" is
slightly more complicated.
忍野姓についてはもう少し込み入った事情もある
But it is certain that her claim
of being Meme's niece is a lie.
しかし メメの姪というのが嘘であるのは確かだ
If Ougi Oshino isn't Ougi Oshino,
then what in the world is she?
忍野扇が 忍野扇ではないのだとすれば
じゃあ あの子はいったい 何なんです?
What is she, really?
あの子の正体は なんなんですか
What she is, right now, is "an unknown."
正体不明というのが
今のところの彼女の正体だ
That is why it is clear how we will
exterminate her. In my original plan,
だからこそ 退治の手段は明確である
当初のプランでは
Ougi Oshino was going to be exterminated
with the demon sword "Kokoro Watari."
忍野扇の退治にあたっては
妖刀 "心渡" を使うつもりだった
So you were planning to slay Ougi-chan
with the Apparition Killer?
扇ちゃんを
怪異殺しで斬るつもりだったんですか?
Come on, don't glare at me like that.
Which side are you on, exactly?
おいおいそう睨むなよ
きみはいったいどっちの味方だい?
Slaying an apparition with
the Apparition Killer...
怪異殺しで怪異を斬る
Normally, something like that
wouldn't even raise an eyebrow.
本来 何の矛盾も生じない話だ
As a specialist, that's my job.
専門家としてはなすべきことだ
Is that why you created the
demon sword "Kokoro Watari"?
そのためにあなたは
妖刀 "心渡" を 作ったんですか?
The armor worn by the first
minion, Seishiro Shishirui.
最初の眷属
死屍累生死郎が着用していた甲冑(かっちゅう)
The sword was created by reforging it
after it went missing in August.
八月に行方知れずとなっていた
あれを打ち直して作り上げたのだ
I didn't create it to slay Ougi Oshino.
忍野扇を斬ろうと思っていたわけではない
However, I did predict the
appearance of Ougi Oshino.
ただし 忍野扇の登場は予期していた
Hmph. No different than someone
who loots during a riot.
ふん 火事場泥棒みたいな真似をしおってからに
No wonder I felt like that
meal was a bit lacking.
どうりで食いでが足らんかったわけじゃ
Don't say that. That's why I've already
returned it to you, Shinobu-san.
そう言うなよ
だからもうきみに返したじゃないか 忍さん
Based on that comment,
the demon sword "Kokoro Watari" that
was used earlier to play cricket
was not Shinobu's, but apparently
the replica created by Gaen-san.
I no longer have a need for it.
もう必要がなくなったからね
If I can count on Koyomin's assistance,
there's no need to do this the hard way.
こよみんの協力を仰げるとなれば
強硬手段に出る必要はなくなった
As a specialist in exterminating monsters,
I can use the proper means,
妖怪退治の専門家として
真っ当な手段で
the standard approach,
to exterminate Ougi Oshino.
スタンダードな方法で
忍野扇を退治できる
What do you mean by saying you predicted
the appearance of Ougi-chan?
扇ちゃんの登場を予期していたっていうのは
どういう意味ですか?
Well, I'm just speaking from experience.
いや それは単なる経験則だ
I wouldn't say it was exactly
the same as Ougi Oshino...
忍野扇と同じ...
とは言わないまでも
but I've seen an apparition
similar to her in the past.
似たような怪異を
かつて私は見たことがあってね
Strictly speaking, I was not the
one that experienced it.
厳密に言うと
経験したのは私ではなく
It was my older sister, Tooe Gaen.
私の姉だった
臥煙遠江(とおえ)だった
You know well of Suruga Kanbaru...
it's her mother.
きみのよく知る神原駿河
その母親だ
Tooe Gaen
In a way, she was like you, Koyomin.
ある種 こよみんに似ていた
As a grade school student, I thought
my older sister was bad news.
小学生ながら
この姉はやばいと思った
I was well aware that she
was a dangerous individual.
危険人物だと痛感していた
How do I put it...
なんて言うんだろうな...
She wasn't a monster,
but she was like a monster.
化物ではないが 化物じみていた
Tough on herself, and tough on others.
自分に厳しく 他人に厳しい
The tougher it got, the more
she thought it was for good.
厳しければ厳しいほど
それを善だと思っている
That's the type of person she was.
そういう人だったよ
But I digress. It's not that I want to
introduce my older sister's personality to you.
しかし それはまあ 余談だ
私の姉のパーソナリティを紹介したいわけではない
For now, I just want to say that such a
personality my older sister had reminds me of Koyomin.
今はただ 私の姉のそういう性格は
こよみんを連想すると言いたいだけだ
Tough on oneself, and tough on others?
Did I have that kind of a personality?
そんな性格だっけ 僕
I will have Koyomin do the same
thing my older sister did.
私の姉と同じことをこよみんにやってもらう
I'm going to do it? Not you, Gaen-san?
僕がやるんですか?
臥煙さんじゃなく?
You're the only one that can do it.
きみにしかできない
You. By yourself.
きみが一人で
You must do it.
やらなければならない
People just...
help themselves
out on their own.
The threat that the unknown
apparition Ougi Oshino poses...
正体不明の怪異である忍野扇の脅威はね
...ultimately boils down to one point,
that she is an unknown.
究極的には
正体不明であるという一点に尽きる
Therefore, disclosing her true identity
would cause it to collapse.
だからその正体を暴けば 瓦壊する
Collapse
Collapse?
瓦壊?
You could call it "pair
annihilation" as well.
対消滅(ついしょうめつ)と言ってもいいけれど
But what's important here is that she's a
fake, who lies about what she really is.
ここで重要なのは
彼女は自らのあるべき姿を偽る偽物であるという点だ
What happens when that lie is exposed...
その嘘が暴かれたらどうなるか...
Shinobu-san and Hachikuji-chan
should know all too well.
忍さんや八九寺ちゃんは
よく知っているはずだよね
The "darkness".
"くらやみ"
Right. Apparitions that lie about what they are
get swallowed by the "darkness".
そう 己のありかたを偽った怪異は
闇に呑まれる
Especially in her case, she falsified
herself as that "darkness" itself.
特に彼女は
己をそのもの "くらやみ" として 偽った
The punishment for such a rule
violation will be the most severe.
そのルール違反に対する制裁は
熾烈(しれつ)を極めることになるだろう
You reap what you sow.
自業自得という奴だ
Everything she's done around
Koyomin for the past six months,
ここ半年ほどこよみんの周辺で繰り返してきた振る舞いを
all of that will now come
bearing down on her.
振るった猛威を
今度は彼女自身が浴びることになる
Well, an apparition is something
intrinsically of that nature.
まあ 怪異というのは本来
そういうものだ
That is why I call Ougi Oshino
"an ordinary monster."
だから私は 忍野扇を
"普通の化物" と呼ぶ
If you explain an apparition with science,
it turns into an ordinary superstition, right?
Gaen-san, so your older sister defeated
an apparition similar to Ougi-chan...
臥煙さんのお姉さんは そうやって
扇ちゃんに似た怪異
A "darkness", no,
a quasi-darkness, in that manner?
"くらやみ" ならぬ
"くらやみ" もどきを退治したんですか?
Yup, that's right.
うん そう
In my opinion, a quasi-darkness is more
dangerous than the "darkness" itself.
私の見るところ
"くらやみ" よりも "くらやみ" もどきのほうが危険度は高い
It refuses to allow a tidy ending.
そんなご都合主義の解決は許さない
It says that giving everyone
a happy ending is cheating.
みんなが幸せになるような答はズルでしかない
That's how it works.
という姿勢を示すことだろう
That is why we absolutely must
だから 是が非でも今日
settle the score once and for all today,
before the night is over.
今夜中に決着をつけなくてはならないということさ
Please, help me.
助けてください
Could you be on my side?
私の味方になってくれませんか?
Please, help me.
助けてください
I don't know why Ougi-chan said that to me.
In the past,
かつて僕は
there was a time when I rejected a request
from Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade.
キスショット・アセロラオリオン・ハートアンダーブレードからの願いを
蹴ったことがあった
I will give Ougi-chan the
same answer as back then.
そのときと同じ答を 扇ちゃんにも言おう
I understand.
わかりました
I will not save Ougi Oshino. So...
僕は忍野扇を助けません
So, please tell me, Gaen-san.
だから...
だから教えてください 臥煙さん
What is the true identity of the mysterious
transfer student, Ougi Oshino?
謎の転校生 忍野扇の正体を
Her true identity is...
あの子の正体は...
Thank you, Tsukihi-chan. Thanks to you,
it looks like I'll make my deadline.
ありがとう 月火ちゃん
お蔭で締切には間に合いそうだよ
Nothing, it's nothing!
なんのなんの
This is Ran Hokkyokusei, transferring
from Shogo Academy.
I don't know much about manga and stuff.
私 漫画とかよくわかんないんだけど
But Nadeko-chan, how confident
are you about this?
撫子ちゃん どれくらい自信あるの これ?
If you win an award, you get
prize money and stuff, right?
受賞したら賞金とかもらえるんでしょ?
Mm... I don't know.
ん... わかんない
I stopped thinking about confidence
and stuff like that.
自信とか そういうの
考えるのやめたから
Hmm...
ふうん...
There have been people that
said I might have talent.
才能があるんじゃないかって
言ってくれた人もいるけれど
But even for people with talent,
才能のある人でも
sometimes these things just don't work out.
こういうのって
うまくいかないときはうまくいかないわけだし
You won't be at the top tier unless
you believe in your talent.
自分の才能を信じられないと
一流にはなれないよ
Otherwise, you won't have anything to keep you going
when you can't put in any more effort.
努力できなくなったときに
支えとなる軸がなくなるから
This is Ran Hokkyokusei, transferring
from Shogo Academy.
People with only effort will become disheartened
when they can no longer put in that effort.
頑張るだけの人は
頑張れなくなったときに挫折する
It feels kind of like
you're trying to trick me.
信じるって言うか
騙されるって感じなんだけど
I just do what I want to do.
やりたいことをやるだけだよ
No matter how unsightly
or embarrassing it is.
どれだけ不恰好(ぶかっこう)でも
恥ずかしくても
Tsukihi-chan, aren't you like that, too?
月火ちゃんだって
そうじゃないの?
I really don't have things I want to do,
or goals, or stuff of that sort.
私には あんまりやりたいこととか 目標とか
そういうの ないんだよね
That's why I like supporting what
other people do like this, I guess?
ゆえにこうやって
人のやってること応援するのが好きっていうのはあるかな?
Hmm?
ふうん... ?
To me, there isn't anyone else with as clear
a stance on life as you, Tsukihi-chan.
私から見れば 月火ちゃんくらい
生きるスタンスがはっきりしている子って いないんだけど
Hahaha! I'm honored by you saying that.
Just how lucky is Tsukihi-chan?
はっはっは そう言ってもらえると光栄だね
月火ちゃん冥利に尽きるよ
But I'm a bit more nihilistic,
or maybe destructive,
だけど もーちょっと私は 虚無的っていうか
破滅的っていうかだから
so there is a part of me that gets drawn
to people who want to do things.
何かをやりたい人に
引っ張られちゃうところはあるな
Are you talking about
Karen-san or Koyomi-san?
火憐さんや...
暦さんのことを言ってるの?
Well, yeah.
まあそうだね
That, and helping Nadeko-chan's job like this
それに こうやって撫子ちゃんの仕事を手伝ってるのも
is me getting drawn to
Nadeko-chan's enthusiasm.
撫子ちゃんのやる気に引っ張られてる感じかな
Job...
仕事...
It's not my job at all yet.
仕事じゃないけどね
まだ 全然
I wonder what eventually
happens to people like me?
私みたいな奴は
将来どうなるんだろうね?
I have to think about planning for
the future before it's too late.
今のうちに将来設計
考えないといけないんだよね
Karen-chan is entering high school,
and Big Brother will be going to college.
火憐ちゃんも高校生になるし
お兄ちゃんも大学生になるし
A normal middle school girl
who goes to 15 Academy!
Because right now I'm getting a taste of being
left behind for the second time in my life,
小学六年生のとき以来二年振り二度目の
But what was
that guy's problem?
And it feels like
I've seen him before...
the last time being two years ago
when I was in sixth grade,
置き去りにされる気分を味わう今だからこそ
What's going to happen to
my ordinary school life?
I should decide what I want
to do, who I want to be.
自分がどうしたいのか 何になりたいのか
決めたいよね
Just like you, Nadeko-chan.
撫子ちゃんみたいに
Just having you say something
like that, Tsukihi-chan,
月火ちゃんにそんなことを言ってもらえただけでも
makes it worth putting effort into this.
頑張っている甲斐があるなあ
Even if people can't become happy, good things
happen to them... as long as they are alive.
人間 たとえ幸せにはなれなくっても
いいことはあるんだよね 生きてたら
Hmm... Well, I guess that's true.
ふむ... まあ そうかもね
Oh? Is that... Araragi-senpai's
little sister right there?
おや そこにいるのは
阿良々木先輩の妹ちゃんじゃあないのかな?
I met you yesterday, too. Hello.
昨日も会ったね
こんにちは
Hello.
Did I meet her?
会ったっけ?
My name is Ougi Oshino. I hear much
about you from your big brother.
私は忍野扇と言うんだよ
お兄さんからきみのことはよく聞いているよ
He says he's very proud of you.
自慢の妹だってね
Okay...
It's getting late, so I'll take
you home. Hop on back here.
もう遅いし 送ってあげるよ
後ろに乗りな
Was Sengoku-chan doing well?
千石ちゃんは 元気だったかな?
How was her electrocardiogram (shindenzu)?
彼女の心電図はどんな感じだった?
Was she dead-zu (shindenzu)?
Or not dead-zu?
死んでんず? それとも死んでないず?
Dead-zu?
Not Dead-zu?
She's all right, I guess.
元気と言えば元気ですよ
She's not dead. If anything, it's more
like she had been dead before now.
死んではないです
死んでたのは むしろ今までのほうだったんじゃないかな
Perhaps.
かもねえ
Well, they say that everybody has something
more to them than just being cute.
うん まあ
可愛いだけの人間なんていないって話だ
The way I think, girls like that
are cuter when they aren't cute.
私が思うに
ああいう子は可愛げがないほうが 可愛いよ
Good, good.
よかったよかった
Being a "pretty girl" ended
up only being a blade
プリティ・ガールであることは
千石ちゃんにとっては
Sengoku-chan used to inflict
wounds on herself.
己を傷つける刃(やいば)にしかならなかったという話だ
Things like that are so sad.
そういうのって 悲しいよね
Sad? Aren't you lucky if you are cute?
悲しい?
可愛ければラッキーじゃないんですか?
For Sengoku-chan, cuteness was also
a chain to bind herself with.
千石ちゃんにとっては可愛さは
自分を縛る鎖でもあっただろうが
But still, I'm sure it was too precious
a talent to get rid of on her own.
それでも自分で切り離すには
惜しい才能だっただろうからね
She needed some drastic measures.
荒療治が必要だったんだよ
Drastic measures?
What are you talking about?
荒療治? って
なんのことですか?
Who knows? I don't.
さあ 知らない
I don't know anything.
私は何も知らないんだよ
Araragi-senpai is the one that knows.
阿良々木先輩が知っているんだ
Sengoku-chan seems to want to become
a manga artist in the future.
千石ちゃんは
将来漫画家になりたいみたいだけれど
Tsukihi Araragi-chan,
what do you want to become?
阿良々木月火ちゃん
きみはどうなりたい?
What I want to be?
どうって
I don't really have anything.
そういうのは 私はあんまりないです
I'm fine as long as I'm
enjoying the present.
今が楽しきゃいいって感じです
I feel like times like that link
together to form the future.
そういうのが繋がって
将来になるのかなーって
You're not the type that knows everything,
きみは何でも知っているというタイプではないけれど
but you are the type that
can do everything.
それでも何でもできるタイプだからね
You may not be omniscient,
but you are omnipotent...
全知ではなくとも全能ではある
きみには選択肢が多過ぎて
You have too many choices,
and so your objectives may be
scattered all over the place.
目標が分散するというのはあるだろう
Though I say future...
将来と言っても...
...your future is much too large in scale.
きみの将来は あまりに遠大だが
Are you saying that I'm too dependent?
私は依存心が強いって意味ですか?
Tsukihi-chan, it's a fact that you live
based on support from those around you.
月火ちゃん きみが
周囲からの支えによって生きているのは
They are keeping you alive.
生かされているのは確かだよ
Without your big brother
and big sister's help,
お兄ちゃんやお姉ちゃんの気遣いがなければ
you could've died during summer break.
きみは夏休みに死んでいてもおかしくはなかった
During summer break?
夏休みに?
The thing about people is,
they can't live all alone!
人は一人では生きていけないって奴ですね
People live of their own accord.
人はひとりでに生きていくものだよ
What can't live of their own accord...
are monsters.
ひとりでに生きていけないのは
化物だ
Just like you and me.
私やきみがそうであるように
Oh... huh?
って あれ?
Wait, Oshino-san...
ちょ 忍野さん
"Ougi-san" is fine.
扇さんでいいよ
Ougi-san, this isn't the right way at all.
扇さん 全然違う方向来てますけど?
Whoa. Sorry, sorry. It looks
like I've gotten lost.
おっと ごめんごめん
道に迷ってしまったみたいだね
Let's stop for a moment and check
the map on a smartphone.
一旦停めて
スマホで地図でも確認しようか
Private Property                    No Entry
Danger            Watch Your
Stay Out!            Head
Danger
No Entry
Stay Out!
Danger           Danger
Warning
Watch Your Head         Danger
Huh?
あれ?
Oh, that's right.
あ... そうだ
Wasn't this the building that burned
down back around August?
これ 八月くらいに
火事で焼けたビルじゃなかったっけ... ?
No Entry
Danger           Danger
Warning
Watch Your Head         Danger
Wow, how strange.
So this is like the ghost of a building?
へえ... 奇妙だねえ
つまりこれは 建物の幽霊って奴なのかな
Why don't we try going in?
ちょっと這入ってみよっか
A school... No, it looks like
it used to be a cram school.
学校... いや
塾 だったみたいですね
Yeah, it seems that way.
ふむ そのようだね
Oh my.  It was so exciting to come barging in
like this, but now we know exactly what it is.
おやおや 勢い殴り込んでみたものの
あっさり正体が割れてしまったか
When we figure out its true identity,
it ceases to be scary at all.
正体がわかってしまうと
怖くもなんともないねえ
Mystery novels are like that, too.
推理小説でもそうだよね
You read them on the edge of your seat, heart
racing, because you don't know who did it.
どきどきはらはらしながら読むのは
犯人がわからないからだ
When the mystery is no longer a mystery,
and the number of suspects is down to one...
謎が謎でなくなり
容疑者が一人に絞られてしまえば
Honestly, after that point, it's no fun.
はっきり言って
そのあとは興ざめだよね
I wish all solution scenes
were just one line long.
謎解きのシーンなんて
一行で終わってくれていい
When the true identity is known,
正体がばれれば
the fear and the fun disappear.
That's how things are.
恐怖も面白味も 消滅する
そういうものだ
Emergency Exit
Do you really think so?
そうですかね?
Danger
Well, in a mystery novel,
that might be right.
いや 推理小説だったらそうかもしれませんけれど
But in reality, doesn't it get scarier
after the culprit is caught?
現実だったら
犯人が捕まったあとのほうが怖くないです?
You confirmed the existence
of something that scared you.
それまで怖いと思っていた対象の
実在を確認できちゃったわけですから
Cram School
Oh?
ほう...
The real story only begins when
you know what they really are.
正体が割れることで話が始まっちゃうって言うか
Emergency Exit
I mean, all the paperwork and stuff after
the culprit is caught takes way longer, right?
実際 犯人が逮捕されてからの手続きのほうが長いでしょう?
Unauthorized Entry Forbidden
Trespassers Will Be Reported to the Police
Besides, you say the true identity,
but it's not always going to be correct.
それに 正体って言っても
それが正しいとは限らないでしょう
There actually might be an even
bigger unexpected plot twist,
実は更なるどんでん返しが待ち受けているかも
if you're talking mystery novels.
推理小説的には
Danger
That may be true. I see, "true identity"
is written as the "right body."
それは そうかもね なるほど
正しい体(てい)と書いて 正体か
True identity
(right) (body)
Danger
In the end, a body is merely a body.
体は所詮 体でしかない
Cram School
You got one on me there. Nothing less
from Araragi-senpai's little sister.
これは一本取られたよ
さすがは阿良々木先輩の妹だ
Tsukihi-chan, they may have
accepted your true identity.
月火ちゃんは
その正体を受け入れられて
Or perhaps they're amused by it.
あるいは 面白がってもらえるかもしれないけれども
But, the same probably
won't happen for me.
私はそうはいかないだろうからね
My true identity is... unsightly.
私の正体は... 醜い
Tsukihi-chan, unfortunately for you,
月火ちゃん
きみには残念ながら
what you call a "future"
doesn't actually exist.
およそ将来と呼べるようなものはない
It's not that you don't know what will
happen in the future. There is no future.
将来どうなるかわからないんじゃない
将来がないんだ
No matter how much of the present you
pile up, it won't lead to a future.
今をどれだけ積み重ねても
将来には繋がらない
All you have is an eternal present.
きみにあるのは永遠の今だけだ
Even so, are you able to live in the present,
それでもきみは 将来を気にせず
without heeding what is to come,
with disregard of the future?
未来にとりあわず
今を生きていられるかな?
Well, probably. I'm pretty good at living.
まあ たぶん
私って 生きるの結構 得意ですから
It's a marvelous thing
that you can say that.
それが言えるのは 素晴らしいことだ
I'm jealous.
羨ましいよ
You're late, Ougi-chan.
遅かったね 扇ちゃん
I've been waiting for you.
待ちかねたぜ
Tsukihi-chan, I'm sorry, but can you take
my bike and go home alone?
月火ちゃん 自転車乗ってっちゃっていいから
悪いけれど一人で先に帰ってもらえるかな
No Entry
Danger           Danger
Warning
Watch Your Head       Danger
I have something important to talk
about with your big brother.
私はこれから
お兄ちゃんと大切な話があるから
The combination on the chain is "1-2-3-4."
チェーンの暗証番号は "１２３４" だ
What is Shinobu-chan doing right now?
忍ちゃんは今 どうしているんですか?
She's supposedly back in
her complete form now...
完全体に復帰したはずですけれど...
She's not together with you?
ご一緒ではないんですか?
That hasn't happened yet.
それは まだだよ
We decided that we will bind
ourselves to one another
再び お互いでお互いを縛り合うのは
once again after everything
is said and done.
すべてが終わってからにしようということに決めた
Hmm...
ふうん?
Shinobu-chan wished to end up
right where she started, huh?
忍ちゃんは
元の木阿弥(もくあみ)になることを望みましたか
And Araragi-senpai, you want
to become a quasi-human,
そして阿良々木先輩は 再び
人間もどきの
a failed attempt at being
a vampire once again?
出来損ない吸血鬼になろうと言うのですか
I just love young girls.
幼女が好きなだけさ
I answer,
while feeling that this
conversation is meaningless.
So what will happen to the girl?
で 少女のほうは どうなる運びに?
She will be enshrined at
North Shirahebi Shrine.
北白蛇神社に祀られる
That also is for when everything
is said and done.
それもまた
すべてが終わってからの話だけどな
Hmm. So that shrine...
ふむ... あの神社を
It was a big problem, what to do with
the giant hole that opened in this town.
この町に開いた大穴を果たしてどうするかというのは
やはり課題でしたが
You sure found a convenient
solution for it.
都合よく解決したものですねえ
A problem... Your job?
課題 きみの仕事というわけかな?
Well, yes. I said something
like that at some point.
まあ そうです
いつか言いましたね そんなこと
No Entry
Danger             Danger
Warning
Watch Your Head         Danger
Speaking of jobs... My little sister...
仕事と言うなら 僕の妹
What kind of lively conversations
did you have with her?
あいつとはどんな話で盛り上がったんだ?
I didn't even get to finish.
話は全然途中でしたよ
It's a shame. My job
ended up being half-done.
残念無念 私の仕事は中途半端で終了したわけです
That was a tough one.
ありゃあ手ごわい
Nothing less from a phoenix.
It's beyond what I can handle.
さすがは不死鳥 手に負えませんね
How in the world was Yoduru Kagenui going to
exterminate such a long-living creature?
影縫余弦は いったいどうやって
あんな長命種を退治するつもりだったんだか
You can exterminate monsters when you
disclose their true identities, right?
化物は 正体を暴けば退治できるんだろ?
That's why I'm saying it doesn't
look like you can exterminate
だから あの子は正体を暴いても
her even if you disclose
her true identity.
退治できそうもないと言っているんですよ
Because she has a big brother
正体を知りながらも
that refuses to stop loving her, even
knowing what her true identity is.
しつこく愛してくれるお兄さんがいらっしゃるわけですからね
Mm... That may be why
Yoduru Kagenui had given up.
ふん だからこそ影縫余弦は投げ出したのかもしれませんが
But I'd surmise that I can't
quite do the same thing.
まあ 私ではとても
そういうわけにはいかないでしょうね
Isn't that so?
そうでしょう?
Araragi-senpai will disclose my true identity,
and I'll be exterminated right here.
私はここで
阿良々木先輩に正体を暴かれて退治される
That's how this works, right?
そういう流れなんでしょう?
A one-on-one duel, as they say.
一対一での決闘ってわけだ
That is quite exciting.
そりゃあ心躍りますねえ
This time, it's something
that I have to do myself.
今回は 僕がやらなきゃいけないことだと思っているよ
It's something that only I can do.
僕にしかできないことだと
And it's something that
I want to do alone.
僕が一人でやりたいことだと
What you "want to do," huh?
やりたいこと... ねえ?
Perhaps you only think that because those
adults smooth-talked you into it?
大人に言いくるめられて
そう思っているだけじゃないですか?
Araragi-senpai, you may think you
are working yourself to the bone
阿良々木先輩は忍ちゃんや八九寺ちゃんのために
身を粉(こ)にしているつもりかもしれませんが
for the sake of Shinobu-chan
and Hachikuji-chan.
But isn't that just habit?
それって惰性と何が違うんです?
How foolish.
愚かですねえ
One tends to find excessive value
in something that was almost lost.
失いかけたものには過度な価値を見出しがちですけれど
But if you bind yourself to such nostalgia,
you will never ever arrive at your future.
そういったノスタルジィに縛られていたら
いつまでたっても将来に辿り着けませんよ
Oh, let me just make it clear that
this is me pleading for my life.
あ 一応言っておきますけれど
これ 命乞いですから
Pleading for your life?
命乞い?
I've been telling you, haven't I?
だから言ったでしょう?
"Could you be on my side?"
私の味方をしてくれませんか って
"Please, help me."
私を助けてください って
It seems that those requests were
fleeting and flatly denied.
どうやらその頼みは
はかなくも無下にされてしまったようですけれど
Was I not charming enough?
私に魅力が欠けていましたかね
Well, that is the correct
answer, Araragi-senpai.
まあそれが正解ですよ 阿良々木先輩
That is the right thing.
それが正しいです
What, so you can do the right thing, too?
なんだ 正しいこともできるんじゃないですか
Unfortunately, I wanted
you to decline that.
残念ながら 断って欲しかったんですよ
私は
Well, this party hasn't quite
gotten into full swing yet,
では 宴もたけなわではございませんが
but let's have you close it
out now, Araragi-senpai.
阿良々木先輩に締めてもらいましょうか
Yeah, I'll have the honor of doing so.
ああ そうさせてもらうよ
Ougi-chan, your true identity...
扇ちゃん きみの正体は...
Your true identity... is me.
きみの正体は 僕だ